Guide to the Franco Modigliani papers, 1936-2005 and undated, bulk 1970s-2003 RL.00905
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2009-0114), 1930s-2003, 7 boxes
  - Videotapes (Box 1)
    - Visita a Valencia del Dr. Franco Modigliani (Box 1)
    - The Exiles: New School (Box 1)
    - Serino (Naples) in Italian for Tourists (Box 1)
    - Giia in Puglia, 1993 (Box 2)
    - CNBC Europe interview, London, Feb. 1998 (Box 2)
    - Bloomberg TV, Franco Modigliani speech (Box 2)
    - President Clinton on the Lewinski affair (Box 2)
  - Audiocassettes (4) (Box 2)
  - Capco Institute Journal of Financial Transformation, Sept. 2003 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and faxes, 1980s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Clippings, mostly 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Modigliani vitae/bibliography (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 2)
    Writing fragments, notes, photocopied articles, Macroeconomics Dynamics correspondence (2000), lecture advertisement (1985).
  - New School conference folder, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Newspapers and magazines with articles on Modigliani, 1964-2003 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and faxes, 1980s-1990s (Box 3)
  - Clippings, mostly 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Condolence cards to Serena Modigliani, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Videotapes with appearances by Franco Modigliani
    - Silent Stars, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Killian Lecture: Applications of the Life Cycle Hypothesis to Policy Issues, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Killian Lecture: Lifecycle Hypothesis of Savings, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Scientia Prog., 122 (Box 3)
    - Problemi sul Dollaro, 1987 (Box 3)
    - First Annual Pacific-Basin Finance Conference (Box 3)
    - Professor Franco Modigliani, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Modigliani-Genoa, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Appointment books, 1996-2003 (Box 4)
  - Books (Box 5)
    - Meyer Burstein, Money (inscribed to Modigliani, with Modigliani's notes) (Box 5)
    - Oscar Lange, Price Flexibility and Employment (with Modigliani's notes) (Box 5)
    - Readings in Monetary Theory (with Modigliani's corrections to his article) (Box 5)
  - Magazines, reprints, articles about Franco Modigliani, 1965-2001 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Tim Kutscheid, prison inmate, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
  - Drafts of working papers (Box 6)
    - Memorandum on the Set-Up and Management of a Proposed International Monetary System, Jan. 31, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Current Economic Developments and their Implications for Monetary Policy, Mar. 5, 1965 (Box 6)
    - The Term Structure of Interest Rates: A Reexamination of the Evidence, Feb. 1969? (Box 6)
    - The Transmission of Demand Fluctuations through a Distribution and Production System, the TV Set Industry, Jan. 1968 (Box 6)
  - Clippings, magazines, publicity materials (Box 6)
  - Articles (Box 6)
  - 3 tobacco pipes (Box 6)
  - Audiocassette tapes (Box 6)
  - Books from graduate school work, 1941-1944 (Box 7)
    - Frederick C. Mills, Statistical Methods Applied to Economics and Business (with Modigliani's notes) (Box 7)
    - Gustavo del Vecchio, Lezioni di Economia Pura (with notes) (Box 7)
    - Garrett Birkhoff, Survey of Modern Algebra (with Modigliani's notes) (Box 7)
    - J.R. Hicks, A Contribution to the Theory of the Trade Cycle (with Modigliani's notes) (Box 7)
    - Maxime Bocher, An Introduction to Higher Algebra (with Modigliani's notes) (Box 7)
    - Henry Burchard Fine, Calculus (with Modigliani's notes) (Box 7)
    - J.M. Keynes, The General Theory of Employment, Interest, and Money (with notes: some by Modigliani, some by another) (Box 7)
    - Jan Tinbergen, Statistical Testing of Business-Cycle Theories, vol. 2 (with Modigliani's notes) (Box 7)
  - Graduate diplomas (Oversize-folder 1)